Guide to the Atwell Loomis Bohling collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Atwell Loomis Bohling collection
1899-1963
MS 1621
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The collection consists of autographed correspondence, printed material, and photographs of government figures such as Woodrow Wilson, Harry S. Truman, Dwight D. Eisenhower, and their colleagues. Printed material and ephemera pertaining to the United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, 1945, is included in the collection.
Bohling, Atwell Loomis, 1922-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Atwell L. Bohling in 1991, in honor of James W. Powell, Class of 1945; gift of Atwell L. Bohling, 1997.
Scope and Contents
The Atwell Loomis Bohling Collection consists of signed/autographed correspondence, printed material, and photographs of government figures such as Woodrow Wilson, Harry S. Truman, Dwight D. Eisenhower, and their associates.
This collection was donated by Atwell L. Bohling in 1991 in honor of James W. Powell, class of 1945.
Biographical / Historical
Atwell Loomis Bohling was born in 1922. He atttended Smith-Cotton High School in Sedalia, Mo. He attended Yale from September 1941 to February 1943 and from July 1946 until he received his B.A. in August 1947. He served in the Army during his hiatus from Yale, and he was discharged as seargent in 1946. He was a government major and member of calhoun. Bohling was also a graduate student from 1947-1948. He was a staff member with the Kansas City Star. He was a reporter until July, 1950 and then a copy editor and headline writer afterwards/ He also was chairman of the board of Jared Eliot Associates.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Bohling, Atwell Loomis, 1922-; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924
- Inventory, 1899-1963
  - Baker, Newton D., 1917 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bryan, William J., 1909 February (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Colby, Bainbridge, 1920 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daniels, Josephus: autobiographical sketch for The Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1961 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Houston, David F., 1913 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Landon, Alf M., 1963 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lansing, Robert, 1915 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McAdoo, William G., 1899 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bulletins announcing the death of Joseph Stalin, Prime Minister of the Soviet Union, [1953 March 5] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Truman, Harry: photocopies of signed photographs, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dedication ceremony of the Harry S. Truman Library: press information (autographed by Harry S. Truman, Eleanor Roosevelt and other participants), 1957 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wilson, Ellen A.: photocopies of correspondence, 1912 January 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wilson, Woodrow: photocopies of correspondence, 1907-1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Additional Material, 1945; Accession 1997-M-158
  Scope and Contents
  This addition to the Atwell L. Bohling Collection consists of printed material and ephemera pertaining to the United Nations Conference on International Organization held in San Francisco, California, in 1945.
  - United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945
    - General [background material relating to and provided for participants] (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Armenia (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Australia (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Belgium (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - China (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ecuador (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Egypt (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - France
      - General (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - France Journal (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Great Britain
      - British Information Services [newsletters, indices to articles]
        - 1943 Dec, 1945 Mar, April 24-May 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - 1945 May 6-25 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - 1945 May 26-June 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - 1945 June 11-27, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Daily Mail (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - India (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Italy (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Korea (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Lebanon
      General
      See: Syria
    - Lithuania (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Poland (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - South Africa (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Soviet Union (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Spain (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Syria/Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - United States
      - American Bar Association/National Lawyers Guild (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - American Jewish Conference (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - American Legion (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - American Veterans Committee (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service [Federal Communications Commission] (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Ukrainian Congress Committee of America (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - United Nations Information Office [primarily biographical sketches of delegates] (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - World Citizenship Movement, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Uruguay (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 2, Folder 36)